Guide to the Boyce D. McDaniel papers, 1933-2002.
McDaniel, Boyce D. papers, 1933-2002
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Boyce D. McDaniel papers, 1933-2002.
14-22-3242
Boyce D. (Boyce Dawkins), McDaniel 1917-2002
12.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, videotapes, technical drawings, academic papers, books, certificates
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal and Professional papers and correspondence relating to his work at Newman Laboratory and in the Physics Department, especially files relating to the Cornell Electron Storage Ring (CESR) and the Superconducting Supercollider (SSC). Also includes information about Robert Wilson and his memorial service.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Physicist.
Professional papers and correspondence relating to his work at Newman Laboratory and in the Physics Department, especially files relating to the Cornell Electron Storage Ring (CESR) and the Superconducting Supercollider (SSC). Also includes information about Robert Wilson and his memorial service.
Personal papers, including diplomas and certificated; photographs; files about his retirement celebration; obituaries and memorial statements; and clippings.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McDaniel, Boyce D.1917-2002; Wilson, Robert R., 1914-2000; Cornell University. Dept. of Physics.
Subjects:
Physicists.; Superconducting Super Collider.; Nuclear physics.; Electrons--Capture.; Particle acceleration.; Neutrons.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Box 12-14: restricted to permission of the Archivist
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biography
Box 1, 8, 17-18
Series II. Correspondence
Box 1
Series III. Cornell University
Boxes 1-3
Series IV. Non-Cornell
Boxes 3-4
Series V. Proposals
Boxes 1-4
Series VI. Publications
Boxes 4-5
Series VII. Conferences/Talks/Reports
Box 5
Series VIII. Honors
Boxes 6, 8-10
Series IX. Plans/Drawings/Charts
Boxes 8, Mapcase
Series X. Photographs
Boxes 5-6,10
Series XI. Videotapes
Box 7
Series XII. Transparencies
Box 5
Series XIII. Miscellaneous Materials
Boxes 5, 11
Series XIV. Restricted Materials
Boxes 12-14
Series XV. Binder Materials
Boxes 15-16
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biography
  - Autobiographical letter, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diplomas - Boyce and Jane McDaniel, Doctor of Philosophy (Cornell), 1943 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Personal, 1943-2002 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Diplomas - Chesterfield High, Ohio Wesleyan, etc, 1933-1937 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Diploma - Case School, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Phi Kappa Phi certificate, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - McDaniel's Australian photographs, ca. 1962 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Retirement celebration, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Retirement celebration photographs, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Obituaries, memorial statements, etc, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Pocket diaries, address books, 1980-1989 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Pocket diaries, 1989-2001 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, 1946-1985 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - 3 photograph albums (Box 18)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - McDaniel Correspondence, Apr. 1970 - June 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - McDaniel Correspondence, July 1970 - Dec. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - McDaniel Correspondence, Jan. 1971 - June 30, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - McDaniel Correspondence, July 1, 1971 - Dec. 31, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - McDaniel Correspondence, Jan. 1, 1971 - Dec. 31, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - McDaniel Correspondence, Jan. 1, 1973 - June 30, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - McDaniel Correspondence, July 1, 1973 - Dec. 31, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - McDaniel Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - McDaniel Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Supporting letters CB (Colliding Beam), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series III. Cornell University
  - Laboratory of Nuclear Studies (LNS)
    - X, 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - LNS Department Organization, 1960-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - LNS Department Organization, 1942-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - LNS, 1948-1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - LNS, 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - LNS CSDS, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - LNS: Letters 10 GeV, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - LNS CS, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - LNS 10 GeV, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - LNS 10 GeV, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - LNS Letters, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Circuit Manual, LNS (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - LNS Synchrotron progress report (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - LNS Cornell 300-Mev Synchrotron, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - LNS Cornell Bev Synchrotron, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - LNS 2 Gev correspondence, Aug. 1962 - Feb. 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - LNS 2 Gev [correspondence], Feb. 1964- Nov. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - LNS 2 Gev Disposal, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - LNS Budget 2.2 NSF GP6276, 9/1966-8/1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - LNS 2.2 Gev Magnet, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - LNS 2.2 Gev Design (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - LNS 10 Bev Synchrotron Mse Reports, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - LNS Magnetic Meas. 10 Gev, 1954-1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - LNS 10 Gev Synchrotron, 1962-1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - LNS Apparatus, 1976-1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - LNS Orders, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - LNS 10-20 Gev Cornell Electron Synchrotron, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - LNS Cornell Electron Synchrotron, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - LNS Status of Cornell 10 G3v Accelerator Facility, NSF Review, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - LNS Miscellaneous Lab Documents, Historical, 1949-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - LNS 10 Gev Historical, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - LNS 10 Gev Alignment, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - CESR (Cornell Electron Storage Ring)
    - CESR: History, 1970-1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - C.E.S.R., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - CESR II Cornell, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - CESR: Gennuth Interview with B. D. M. for AIP (American Institute of Physics), 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - CESR: Coil Epoxy R. Ehlicks note for CESR, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - CESR: Multi-bunch Pretzel, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - CESR: Miscellaneous notes, 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - CESR: Dipole, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - CESR: Magnetic Test Forms, 1951, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - CESR: Magnetic Measurements, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Super CESR Machine Upgrade, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - CESR: IR Quads, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - CESR: IR Quad (Quadrupole potting fixture), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - CESR: IR Quads, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - CESR: View Graphs and Miscellany, 1963-1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - CESR: Reprints, 1962-1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - CESR: Design Report, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - CESR: Design Report, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - CESR Annual Report (LNS), 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - CESR: NSF Agreement Quarterly Report, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - CESR: Annual Progress Report and Request for Continued Support, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - CESR: Annual Progress Report and Request for Continued Support, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - CESR: Annual Progress Report and Request for Continued Support, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - CHESS (Cornell High Energy Synchrotron Source)
    - CHESS II, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - CHESS: NSF, 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - CLEO
    - CLEO Detector, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - CLEO II Updated Proposal for Improvements to, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Series IV. Non-Cornell
  - LIGO
    - LIGO: Progress Report on Design and Development Study for CESR II High Energy, High Liminosity Electron Positron Collider Based on Superconducting RF Cavities, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - LIGO: User Panel, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - LIGO: User Panel, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - The U. S. LIGO Project, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - SSC (Superconducting Super Collider)
    - SSC Correspondence Tigner, 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - SSC General Correspondence, 1985-1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - SSC Krumhansl Correspondence, 19887-1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers, 1984-1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers - Correspondence Tigner-McD, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers Correspondence Panofsky, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 17-19)
    - SSC: B.D.M. Testimony before International Committee of Future Accelerators, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - SSC Symposium Denver, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - SSC, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - SSC Papers, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - SSC: McDaniel Interview by L. Hoddeson and A. Kolb, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - GAO Report on High Energy Physics, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Series V. Proposals
  - LNS
    - Proposal for a 3Bev Electron Synchrotron at Cornell, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Proposal for 10 Gev Electron Synchrotron at Cornell, addendum, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Proposal to NSF for funds to construct addition to 10 GeV Electron Synchrotron Facility, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Proposal to NSF for operational support, Mar. 1, 1971 - Feb. 29, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - CESR (Cornell Electron Storage Ring)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Mar. 1, 1970 - Feb. 29, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Mar. 1, 1972 - Feb. 28, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Mar. 1, 1975 - Feb. 29, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Construction Funds, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support (2 copies), Mar. 1, 1976 - Feb. 28, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Feb. 1, 1977 - Jan. 31, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - CESR Proposal: An Electron Positron Colliding Beam Facility (2 versions), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Nov. 1, 1979 - Oct. 31, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Nov. 1, 1980 - Oct. 31, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Nov. 1, 1981 - Oct. 31, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - CESR Upgrade Proposal, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Nov. 1, 1982 - Oct. 31, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Nov. 1, 1983 - Oct. 31, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Nov. 1, 1984 - Oct. 31, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Nov. 1, 1985 - Oct. 31, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - CESR Proposal to NSF for Operational Support, Nov. 1, 1987 - Oct. 31, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - CESR/CLEO (Cornell University Laboratory for Elementary-Particle Physics) Upgrade Project Proposal (3 parts), 1993-1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - CESR: Proposal to NSF for Operational Support of CESR Facility, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - CLEO
    - CLEO II Updated Proposal for Improvements to the CLEO Detector for the Study of positron-electron interactions at CESR, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - CLEO Upgrades, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - LIGO
    - LIGO: Design Study Proposal for High Energy, High Luminosity Electron Positron Collider Based on Superconducting Cavities, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - LINAC
    - LINAC: NSF Proposal re Phase I Energy Recovery LINAC (ERL) Synchrotron Light Source at C. U., 2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Series VI. Publications
  - B. D. M. thesis: The Absorption of Slow Neutrons in Indium, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - GAO Report: responses, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Reprints and abstracts (B. D. M.), 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Lacquer Film Studies by Electron Diffraction, B. D. M., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Reprints and abstracts, B. D. M., Oct. 1947-1959 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Papers, articles, reprints; B. D. M., 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Reprints, papers, articles; B. D. M., 1974, 1982-1993 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Transcript, clipping, reprint, paper; B. D. M., 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1991, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Publications by/about others, 1940-1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Publications by others, 1972-1988, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, Cornell University article, booklets, 1969-1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Series VII. Conferences/Talks/Reports
  - Positron-electron Ring Conference - papers, etc., 1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Los Alamos, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Report of the 20 Tev Hadron Collider Technical Workshop, Mar. 28, 1983-Apr. 2, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Santa Cruz Accelerator School, Aug, 22, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - AIP, Oct. 1984 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - HEPAP (High Energy Physics and Applied Physics), Apr. 22-25, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - China, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - University of Illinois - Hanson, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Accelerator School Talk, Aug. 11, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Conference notebook, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Los Alamos, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Los Alamos, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Particle Accelerators and How They Are Used (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - John DeWire: eulogies and obituary, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Ruth DeWire: eulogies, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Maury Tigner Retirement Symposium, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - University of Illinois talk, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Series VIII. Honors
  - World's First Pair Spectrometer, B. D. McDaniel, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Boyce McDaniel, Fermilab (plaque), 1974 (Box 10)
  - National Academy of Sciences Certificate, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Retirement book, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Physics 380 - 510, 1945 - 1987 ! (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Series IX. Plans/Drawings/Charts
  - 10 Gev Coils, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Eggcrate Parts, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Proposals and Schedule, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Multibunch Pretzel, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - CESR: IR Quads, 1977, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Tunnel Drawings, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 10 Gev Magnet Assembly, 1964-1966 (Folder 1)
  - 10 Gev Coils, 1965 (Folder 2)
  - Eggcrate Parts, 1987 (Folder 3)
  - Crystal Mandrel, 1986-1987 (Folder 4)
  - Multibunch Pretzel, 1983 (Folder 5)
  - IR Quads (Folder 6)
  - CESR: IR Quads, 1977, 1978 (Folder 7)
  - SSC Project Summary, Network, Preliminary, 1992 (Folder 8)
  - C-Magnet, Proposals, unidentified, 1947, 1965, n.d. (Folder 9)
  - CESR: Large Quadrupole Magnet Assembly, 1977 (Folder 10)
- Series X. Photographs
  - Fermilab and Wilson Photos, 1968, 1972, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Mechanical Resonance Photos (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Cyclotron Photos (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - LNS - McD - 300 Mev Photos (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - LNS 1.4 Gev [Synchrotron] Photos (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - LNS 2.2 Gev Photos (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - LNS 10 Gev I (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - LNS 10 Gev II Photos (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - CESR Photos (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - SSC: Magnets, [1988] (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - LNS 10 Bev (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - CESR: IR Quad (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - CESR Celebration, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Accelerator School Talk, Aug. 11, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Los Alamos Talk, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Los Alamos Talk, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Particle Accelerators. How they are used (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Bob Matyas, Dale Corson, B.D.M.; C. U. Synchrotron (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Photos MSC (Materials Science Center) (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - B.D.M. in groups, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Bill Woodward (Box 6)
  - Helen Edwards, B.D.M., Morey Tigner (Box 6)
  - Helen Edwards (Box 6)
  - Helen Edwards (Box 6)
  - Robert Wilson (Box 6)
  - To B.D.M. from DESY (Deutsches Elektronen-Synchrotron) to commemorate years of friendly competition [Hamburg], 1985 (Box 6)
  - "To Boyce McDaniel with thanks from SSRL for service on the Science Policy Board, 1985-1990 (framed photograph) (Box 10)
- Series X. Videotapes
  - Al's Retirement Party, May 12, 1990 (Box 7)
  - Senate SSC Vote, Aug. 3, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Superconducting Super Collider Construction Update, 1993 (Box 7)
  - "I Am Become Death," by Arthur McCaig, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Enola Gay: The First Atomic Mission, 1995 (Box 7)
  - The Oppenheimer Lecture "Plectics: The Study of Simplicity and Complexity," Professor Murray Gell-Mann, University of California, Berkeley, Mar. 30, 1998 (Box 7)
  - ABC "The Century," Los Alamos-Bomb, original, Apr. 1, 1999 (Box 7)
  - ABC News, The Century, "Ultimate Power: the race to build the atomic bomb", Apr. 1, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Robert Wilson Memorial, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Invisible Blessings: A Story of Nuclear Science and Medicine, 2001 (Box 7)
  - McDaniel's Symposium, edited, complete (Box 7)
  - McDaniel's Recollections (Box 7)
  - NBC, Trinity Scientists/Bomb, Wilson (Box 7)
  - ABC "Hitler and the Bomb," Mac and Ken Hartill (Box 7)
  - The High Resolution Fly's Eye Project (Box 7)
  - A Visit to the Wilson Synchrotron Laboratory - C. U. (Box 7)
- Series XII. Transparencies
  - CESR View Graphs and Miscellany, 1982-1987 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Los Alamos, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Transparencies: Administrative and Miscellany, 1982-1992 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - History of Accelerators at Cornell, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Various colliders: SSC, SLAC (Stanford Linear Accelerator Center), [1985] (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - University of Illinois Talk, Oct. 22, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - SSC Magnets (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Accelerator School Talk, Aug. 11, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Kyoto seminar, [1994] (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Los Alamos, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Los Alamos, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - CLEO Experimental View Graph (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Particle Accelerators: How They Are Used (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Tigner Retirement (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Unidentified (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Miscellany (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Drawings/Figures (Box 5, Folder 56)
- Series XIII. Miscellaneous Materials
  - C. U. Faculty Members of the Distinguished National Academies, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Miscellany: John DeWire Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Miscellany: John DeWire Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Miscellany: John DeWire Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Miscellany: Robert R. Wilson Bio NAS (National Academy of Sciences) (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Miscellany: Robert R. Wilson Bio NAS (2) (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Miscellany: Robert R. Wilson Memorial Service, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Miscellany: Wilson Life (Jane Wilson) (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Miscellany: Wilson Obituaries, [2000] (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Cornell Calendars (Box 11)
    Includes 1976-77 - 1979-80, 1982-83 - 1986-87, 1992-93 - 1995-96
- Series XIV. Restricted Materials
  - B.D.M. files
    - Reference letters A-C, 1975-1987 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Reference letters L, [1991?] (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Reference Info. R (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Reference letters S, 1978-1995 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Reference letters T, 1977-1996 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Wilson, 1977-1997 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Wilson 80th: Fermilab and Cornell, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1977 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1992 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1998-2002 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Background for NAS, 1945-1976 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - NAS, 1976-1994 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - MSC, 1951-1993 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - B.D.M. Recognition/Friends' Obituaries, 1997-2002 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - B.D.M. Salary, etc., 1960-1997 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - McDaniel Professorship, 1993, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - B.D.M. Retirement, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - CAPE (Cornell Association of Professors Emeriti), 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Resident's Association Annual Report (Kendal at Ithaca), 1996-97, 1997-98, 2000-01 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Kendal Budget Requests, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Kendal Council Minutes, May 1999 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - [Kendal] Council Minutes, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - CAP [Kendal], 2001 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Operating [Kendal], 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Kendal Property Committee, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - [Kendal] Calendars and Newsletters, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Kendal, 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Councilor's Guide, Resident's Association, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Kendal - Dust, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - KAI-TV [Kendal], 2001 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Kendal Energy Audit, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Kendal Master Landscape Plan (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Structural Investigation, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Transport Vehicles (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Wind Screen, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Wood Shop, 1996, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - Tompkins County Office of Aging Advisory Group, 1990, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - SSC: Personal Notes, 1983-1993 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - SSC: Director, 1984-1988 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - SSC Management: Personal Confidential, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers, Aug. 1992, Feb.-Mar. 1993 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - SSC: Board of Overseers, Apr.-Sept. 1993 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - SSC termination process, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - SSC: Schwitters - Personnel, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - SSC interview, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Panofsky correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Tigner correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - McDaniel to Seznec re personnel matters, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Jane McDaniel Materials
    - J.M. miscellany, 1957-1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Penntonian, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - New Yorker diaries, 1980-1986 (Box 13, Folder 3-9)
- Series XV. Binder Materials
  - Flip Coil Measurements (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - CLEO II Magnet (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Report of the 1975 HEPAP, June 1975 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Cornell Injection, June 22, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - CESR CONV CONS (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - IR Quads (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - CESR Quads (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Biographical Memoirs (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Physical Laboratory Data Book: Integrator Calibration (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - J.W. de Wire Composition Notebook, Aug. 8, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Hard Bends (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Ledger, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Cleo II Magnet (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - SREL-Radioactivity (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - BNL-SREL (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Birdsboro Corporation Corespondence (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Gev-401, Part I (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Gev-401, Part II (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Gev-401, Part III (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - CESR Coil Production (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Radioisotope Inventory Sheets (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Quad Leveling (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Quad Leveling: IR Quads (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Quad Leveling: Rec Quad (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Rotating Quads Q48, 49, 50 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - MDC High Vacuum Components Catalog (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - CESR (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - CESR (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - 10 Gev (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Edwards, Helen, Thesis, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - IR Magnet, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Summary of CESR Magnet Design Parameters (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - CESR Steel (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Synchrotron Project, 1964-1967 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Sumner Rochlin, Robert, Gamma-Rays from Tritium Bombarded by Protons, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Jones, William Burnett Jr., The Absorption of Slow Neutrons by Iodine, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 7)